barratts.co.uk 2008-02-19

# Barratts - Help & FAQ

  * [7\. How long do i have to return an unwanted item and are returns free of charge?](http://www.barratts.co.uk/f/help/Help_and_FAQ.html#q7)
  * [11\. The system is asking for a start date but my card does not have one, what do I do?](http://www.barratts.co.uk/f/help/Help_and_FAQ.html#q11)

## About Us

Barratts Shoes is a trading name of Stylo Barratt Shoes Ltd, which is a wholly owned subsidiary of Stylo plc, based in Bradford, West Yorkshire.

Currently operating out of nearly 200 stores across the United Kingdom and Ireland, Barratts is the UK's second largest independent shoe retailer.

We aim to offer our customers fantastic footwear ranges which represent great value for money for all the family.

## Returns Policy

If you are dissatisfied with the goods for any reason and return the same unworn to us by post within 28 days of delivery we will refund the cost of the goods.

The above is in addition to your statutory rights, which remain unaffected, but we shall not be liable to you or any third party for any indirect or consequential loss or damage.

## Shipping Rules

If the goods you have ordered are in stock, will endeavour to dispatch your order within 48 hours days. However, it is not possible to specify a guaranteed delivery date for orders placed on the internet.

For orders placed within mainland UK a choice of two non-refundable delivery rates are available - PREMIUM for delivery within three working day at a price of £5.95 per order and STANDARD for delivery to your home within 7 days at a price of £2.95 per order. For deliveries to the Republic of Ireland, Northern Ireland and UK off shore a non-refundable delivery rate of £9.95 for delivery within 10 working days will be charged.

Barratts Privacy Policy 

Barratts is committed to protecting the privacy of the personal information you provide us on our website. We believe it is important for you to know what information we collect and how we treat the information you share with us. The following policy will explain how your personal information will be treated as you use our website and its features. 'Personal Information' includes your name, physical address, e-mail address(es), telephone numbers, credit card information and other similar information that you provide to us. We do not sell your Personal Information.

We will only share your Personal Information outside the Stylo family of companies and franchisees with your consent - as required by law or to protect Stylo, its customers or the public, with companies that help Stylo fulfil its obligations with you, and then only with partners who share Stylo commitment to protecting your online privacy.

In each of the instances above, we may ask for your Personal Information in order to provide you the services or offers. In the case of actions listed above, you will be able to 'unsubscribe' to these at any time. It is completely optional for you to register, participate or otherwise provide us with Personal Information in the above situations.

## How your information is used

The information you provide helps Barratts understand how you use our website. This allows us to recognise your needs and continue to make the improvements that are important to you and our customers.

Barratts will not disclose or transfer your Personal Information to third parties without your consent or as otherwise set forth in this privacy policy. If you have opted-in we may use your Personal Information to respond to specific requests and to send notices of new products, special offers and other marketing materials to enhance and support your relationship with Barratts. These communications may take the form of postal mail, telephone calls, e-mail and other methods of contact. Also, agents, service providers and other contractors of Barratts who will have access to your Personal Information are required to keep the information confidential and not use it for any other purpose than to fulfil the services they are performing for Barratts.

Additionally, if you have opted-in to receiving marketing or other information from our third party business partners, you may receive marketing or other communications directly from those third parties. Barratts encourages you to read the privacy policies of each and every third party company and website that collects your Personal Information. However, whether you are receiving mailings directly from us or from our third party business partners, you will be able to 'unsubscribe' to these mailings at any time.

## Unsubscribing and data removal

If your Personal Information changes (such as post code, phone, e-mail or postal address), or if you no longer desire to be contacted about our products and services, you can correct, update or delete/deactivate your Personal Information at any time. This can be done by e-mailing Barratts. If you have previously unsubscribed or opted-out through the Barratts website but you are still receiving notices, offers or solicitation relating to Barratts, it could be that you initially opted-in to receive information in a manner other than through our website (such as a collection and drawing of business cards held at a Barratts retailer units in which the winner is contacted by e-mail). If this is the case, your desire to unsubscribe may also need to be communicated to the original 'opt-in' source. We take your online privacy very seriously, so if you need any assistance in unsubscribing to future communications please contact Barratts. We will promptly take action to ensure that you are 'opted-out' from receiving any further mailing or other information. Although we will remove your name from our e-mail list as quickly as possible, please recognise that there may be a period of time after you unsubscribe during which you may still receive e-mails from us.

## Children's Privacy

Barratts does not seek to collect Personal Information about children through its website and is committed to protecting the privacy of visitors under the age of 18. Parents should supervise the online activities of their children, and consider the use of tools available from online services and software providers that help provide kid-friendly Internet environments.

## Other Sites

Barratts website may contain links to other sites on the Web. The information practices of those websites are not covered by this privacy policy. Although we are committed to protecting your Personal Information, we cannot control and are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such other websites. Barratts encourages you to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personal information. You are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and other account information.

## Modifications of this policy

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. You are responsible for checking this policy when you visit our site to review the current policy. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. If, however, we are going to use your Personal Information different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you via e-mail. You will have a choice as to whether or not you want us to use your Personal Information in this different manner.

## Material Description

##### Uppers

Symbol  | Description   
---|---  
Leather  | This symbol indicates that this part of the shoe is constructed of genuine leather.  
Synthetic  | This symbol indicates that this part of the shoe is constructed from a synthetic material, for example PVC.  
Textile  | This symbol indicates that this part of the shoe is constructed from a textile material, for example Canvas or Raffia.  
Other  | This symbol indicates that this part fo the shoe is constructed from another type of material.  
  
##### Soles

Symbol  | Description   
---|---  
Leather  | This symbol indicates that this part of the shoe is constructed of genuine leather.  
Synthetic  | This symbol indicates that this part of the shoe is constructed from a synthetic material, for example PVC.  
Other  | This symbol indicates that this part fo the shoe is constructed from another type of material.  
  
## Sizing Chart

Mens UK  | Mens Euro  | Ladies UK  | Ladies Euro   
---|---|---|---  
Not Applicable  | Not Applicable  | 1 | 33  
Not Applicable  | Not Applicable  | 2 | 35  
Not Applicable  | Not Applicable  | 3 | 36  
Not Applicable  | Not Applicable  | 4 | 37  
Not Applicable  | Not Applicable  | 5 | 38  
6 | 39 | 6 | 39  
7 | 41 | 7 | 41  
8 | 42 | 8 | 42  
9 | 43 | 9 | 43  
10 | 44 | 10 | 44  
11 | 46 | Not Applicable  | Not Applicable   
12 | 47 | Not Applicable  | Not Applicable   
13 | 48 | Not Applicable  | Not Applicable   
14 | 49 | Not Applicable  | Not Applicable   

## Frequently Asked Questions

### 1\. Do you deliver outside the UK?

No, we only deliver to mainland UK, Southern and Northern Ireland and the Channel Islands. Unfortunately we do not have the facilities to delivery outside these areas or to BFPO or POBOX addresses.

### 2\. When will my goods arrive?

Depending on which delivery option was chosen, goods will arrive within 7 working days if you chose the £2.95 option, or within 3 working days if you chose the £5.50 option. If living in UK offshore or Northern Ireland this takes 7 working days. Southern Ireland deliveries take 10 working days.

### 3\. Can I amend my order?

Unfortunately no amendments can not be made after placing your order.

### 4\. How do I return an unwanted item?

Unwanted items can be posted back to the address given on the invoice, or you can take them back into your local store.

### 5\. How can I choose my postage?

On Stage 2 of the order process you are given the option to change the delivery from default of 7 working days at £2.95 to the 3 working days at £5.50 delivery. For UK offshore addresses and Northern Ireland deliveries, you must select the £9.00 delivery option which will be delivered within 7 working days. For Southern Ireland, you must select the £9.95 delivery option which will be delivered within 10 working days.

### 6\. Can I change my delivery address on a parcel?

No, we cannot amend your delivery address details after your order has been placed.

### 7\. How long do i have to return an unwanted item and are returns free of charge?

You have 28 days to return goods. They must be unworn and in their original packaging. Goods returned over the 28 days will be given a voucher to the current retail value. Returns are not free unless the goods are faulty. However, you can return unwanted items to a Barratts store free of charge.

### 8\. What period of time does a refund take?

As soon as we receive the unwanted goods your account will be credited. Once we have processed the refund, this can take upto 3 working days to show on your bank account.

### 9\. Can I have an exchange?

No, we can only refund your account if your unwanted goods are sent back here. If an exchange is required, this is possible by calling into your local branch and exchanging for the desired product.

### 10\. Why have I not received a confirmation email?

This may be due to our systems not recognising your email address. or an incorrect email address being registered under your account.

### 11\. The system is asking for a start date but my card does not have one, what do I do?

All cards are issued with a start date but are not always evident on the card, please contact your card issuer for further assistance

### 12\. Can I have a parcel delivered to my work address?

Your initial order must be delivered to the address that the card is registered to. After this first order your delivery address can be changed. To have an order delivered to your work address, you must select the £5.50 delivery option.

### 13\. Can I use gift vouchers online?

unfortunately there is no facilities to accept gift vouchers on line at the moment.

### 14\. Will my parcel be left if I am not at home?

Your parcel maybe left in a secure place if you are not home when using the standard £2.95 delivery option or the Courier should leave a card through your door advising of redelivery. If the premium £5.50 delivery is chosen, this has to be signed for and will not be left. You will be left a card through your door advising of redelivery.

### 15\. Is the delivery charge per order or per item?

The delivery you pay It is per order not per item.
